[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We're now down to our final practical issue stochastic gradient,
قد وصلنا الآن إلى المسألة العملية الأخيرة لدينا، فيما يتعلق بالتدرج العشوائي،
which again is going to be an optional section.
والتي ستكون قسمًا اختياريًا في الدورة.
And the question is, how do we introduce regularization and
والسؤال هو، كيف نقوم بإدخال التنظيم؟
what impact it has on the updates.
وما تأثيره على التحديثات؟
And this is going to be pretty significant
حيث سيكون له تأثير هائل،
if you want to implement it yourself in a general way.
إذا كنت ترغب في تنفيذه بنفسك بشكل عام.
Again, optional section because it's pretty detailed.
ومرة أخرى، هذا القسم اختياري، حيث إنه مفصل للغاية.
So let's remind ourselves of the regularized likelihood.
دعونا نذكر أنفسنا بدالة الاحتمالية المنتظمة.
So, we have some total party metric defined in the pit of our data,
لذا، فإن لدينا نوعًا من المقياس الإجمالي للجودة المحدد فيما يتناسب مع البيانات،
which is the log likelihood.
والذي يمثل سجل الاحتمالات.
And some measures of the complex of the parameters which in our case,
ونوعًا من قياس مدى تعقيد المتغيرات،
here we're using w squared, the actual normal for the parameters, and
والتي في حالتنا هذه، سنستخدم تربيع W، وهو القاعدة العامة للمتغير،
we wanted to compute the gradient of this regularized likelihood to
وأردنا حساب معامل التدرج لهذه الاحتمالية المنتظمة
make some progress, and avoid over fitting.
لإحراز بعض التقدم، وتجنب الإفراط في المطابقة.
So, the total derivative is the derivative of the first term, the quality,
لذا، فإن مجموع الكلي للمشتقة، هو عبارة عن مشتقة المصطلح الأول، الممثل في الجودة،
which is the sum over the data points of the contribution of each data point,
والتي عبارة عن مجموع نقاط البيانات مضروبًا في قيمة كل نقطة بيانات،
the thing that got really expensive.
وهو شيء عالي القيمة.
And the contribution of the second one, once we introduced that parameter, lambda,
وبالنسب لقيمة المصطلح الثاني، فبمجرد إدخال ذلك المتغير λ
to trade off the two things, talked about this a lot, contribution is -2 lambda wj.
للمفاضلة بين هذين الأمرين، حيث تحدثنا حول هذا الأمر كثيرًا، فإن القيمة -2 λWj.
And we derive this update
وقد قمنا بتناول هذا التحديث
during an earlier module on regularized logistic regression.
خلال وحدة سابقة حول الانحدار اللوجستي المنتظم.
Now this is how we do straight up gradient updates with regularization.
وهكذا نقوم بإجراء تحديثات مباشرة للتدرج باستخدام التنظيم.
The question is what do we do?
والسؤال هو، ما الذي ينبغي القيام به
We only do stochastic gradient with regularization.
عندما نرغب في تنفيذ التدرج العشوائي باستخدام التنظيم.
So, if you remember stochastic gradient, we just said we take the contribution for
لذا، إذا كنت تتذكر التدرج العشوائي، حيث قلنا إننا نأخذ القيمة
single data point, and
لنقطة بيانات واحدة،
if we added up those contributions we get exactly the gradient.
وإذا قمنا بإضافة تلك القيم، فسنحصل على التدرج بالضبط.
This is why it worked,
وهذا هو السبب وراء نجاح الأمر،
because the sum of these stochastic gradients equal the gradient.
لأن مجموع التدرج العشوائي مساوٍ لقيمة التدرج.
And so, to my theme that, we need to think about how to set up the regularization
وبالتالي، للحفاظ على ذلك، فيجب أن نفكر في كيفية إعداد مصطلح التنظيم
term such that the sum of the stochastic gradients also is equal to the gradient.
حيث إن مجموع التدرج العشوائي مساوٍ أيضًا لقيمة التدرج.
And one way to think about this is that we take the regularization and
والطريقة الوحيدة للتفكير في ذلك، هي أخذ التنظيم
divide it by N.
ونقسمه على N.
So in practice you want to do this.
لذا، فأنت تريد القيام بهذا عمليًا.
You want to say that the total derivative for
ترغب في القول إن المجموع الكلي لمشتقة
stochastic gradient is contribution data point minus two over n lambda wj.
التدرج العشوائي تساوي قيمة نقطة البيانات مطروحة من λ Wj 2.
And so if you were to add this up you get back to the full gradient.
وإذا كنت ستقوم بحساب ذلك، فستحصل على القيمة الكلية للتدرج.
So with regularization now, the algorithm stays the same, but
لذا، بالنسبة للتنظيم الآن، فإن الخوارزمية تظل كما هي،
the contribution data point is its gradient minus two over n lambda wj.
ولكن قيمة نقطة البيانات تساوي التدرج مطروحًا من 2 λ Wj.
That's the contribution from the regularization point.
وهذه هي القيمة التي تحصل عليها بالنسبة للتنظيم.
If you are using mini-batches, you'd adapt that times.
وإذا كنت تستخدم مجموعات صغيرة، فستقوم بمواءمة ذلك ليتم ضربه.
So you had the sum of the contributions from each data point And
لذا، فإن لديك مجموع القيم لكل نقطة بيانات،
then it will be 2 b over n lambda w j.
وستكون 2 على N مضروبة في λ WJ.
So this is how we take care of regularization.
لذا، فهذه هي كيفية التعامل مع التنظيم.
Again very small change, it's going to behave way better.
ومرة أخرى، فهو عبارة عن تغيير بسيط للغاية، ولكنه سيعمل بشكل أفضل.